Bob L. Thomas papers, 1952-1996, undated
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
Bob L. Thomas papers
1952-1996, undated
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials http://www.baylor.edu/lib/bcpm/
92
Bob L. Thomas, 1937 - 1996
10 document boxes
The Bob L. Thomas papers include correspondence, biographical information, clippings, and research notes. The bulk of this collection is court opinions written by Thomas while he presided as a Justice of the Tenth Court of Appeals in Waco, Texas.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Bob L. “Bobby” Thomas was born in Hill County, Texas on February 27, 1937, and moved to Waco, Texas in 1941. At fifteen years old, Thomas showed promise as a track athlete, winning several awards. However, at that same age he contracted Polio which affected his legs and surrendered his life to a wheelchair.
This disability did not deter him. He was a 1955 graduate of Waco High School, completed a BBA in Accounting at Baylor University in 1958, and graduated first in his class from Baylor Law School in 1960. He began his law practice in Waco during 1961, working in tax law as well as general law.
From 1967-1970, Thomas served as a state legislator in addition to his law practice. He ceased both when he was elected as County Judge of McLennan County. He served in this position until 1982, when he became a Justice of the Tenth Court of Appeals.
Bob Thomas was active in his community as well as his profession. He was twice awarded by the Jaycees as an “Outstanding Young Man of Texas” and honored as Texas “Disabled Person of the Year.” Thomas was also a member of the Task Force to revise the Texas Mental Health Code and a consultant to the Commissioner of Texas Rehabilitation Commission, both of which were appointed positions.
In 1989, Thomas was appointed Chief Justice of the Tenth Court of Appeals where he served until his death, February 21, 1996.
Scope and Content
The Bob L. Thomas papers include personal papers as well as court opinions. The personal papers hold correspondence, biographical information, and clippings. An early clipping shares a peek into Thomas’ life prior to contracting Polio, but several are obituaries and memorials written upon his death. Handwritten notes and research materials are also included and were most likely used as Judge Thomas was preparing his Court Opinions. The bulk of this collection consists of Court Opinions prepared for both Civil and Criminal Cases while Thomas served as Justice of the Tenth Court of Appeals.
Arrangement
A previous finding aid was compiled by Ben Van Tang, student assistant. A visible delineation was present between personal and court opinion documents and has been updated to follow archival standards. The collection now has two series, Personal and Court Opinions. The Personal series is further divided into General and Notes, while Court Opinions are arranged by Civil Trials and Criminal Trials.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the W. R. Poage Legislative Library in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 92. Acquired 1997-01-15
Related Resources
Related references
“Bob L. Thomas.” Legislative Reference Library of Texas. Accessed November 2, 2018.
Bob L. Thomas papers, Accession #92, Box 1, Folder 7, Baylor Collections of Political Materials, W. R. Poage Legislative Library, Baylor University.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Thomas, Bob L. -- Archives.
Subjects
Judges -- Texas -- McLennan County.; Legislators -- Texas.; People with disabilities -- Texas.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Records (Documents)
- Personal, 1952-1996, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The Personal series is divided into two subseries, General and Notes. The General subseries, dated 1952-1996, includes clippings, biographical information, and correspondence. Several of the clippings are obituaries or tributes to Judge Thomas upon his death. The Notes subseries, dated 1993-1994, is comprised of handwritten notes and research materials most likely used by Thomas when preparing court opinions. The General subseries is arranged chronologically while the Notes subseries is arranged alphabetically. This series is in good condition.
  - General, 1952-1996, undated; 1
    - Article, Civil Appellate Practice, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Baylor Law Annual Photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1952 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - House Journal Birthday Resolution, 1969 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Handwritten brief regarding wager with Robert Thomas, 1985 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Resume, circa 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Thomas J. Blankenship vs. Texas State Technical College, et. al., 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - HB700, Electing Appellate Court Judges, 1991 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Article, Judicial Decision Making, 1992 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Earl Bracken Jr. Retirement, 1995 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Tributes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Funeral Arrangements, 1996 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notes, 1993-1994, undated; 2
    - 3 P’S sue City, Wasserman and several defendants, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 5th Circuit Cases, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Butler v. State, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Carrow v. Wal-Mart, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Cases citing Marin (851/2/275), undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Contribution, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Definitions, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Family Code, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Libel v. Slander, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Willie Lee McDuff et. al. v. Lester E. Jennings, Chambers Medical and Surgical Clinic et. al., undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Peeler v. Hughes & Luce, 1993 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Questions, Restatement of Agency, Contracts, Corporations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - State v. Bryant, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Voir Dire (1 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Voir Dire (2 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - William Industries v. Eugene and Karen Pribyla (1 of 3), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - William Industries v. Eugene and Karen Pribyla (2 of 3), 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - William Industries v. Eugene and Karen Pribyla (3 of 3), 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Court Opinions, 1982-1996; 2
  The Court Opinions series, dated 1982-1996, covers the expanse of Judge Thomas’ time as Justice of the Tenth Court of Appeals in McLennan County, Texas. This subseries is arranged chronologically by month and year in two subseries, Civil Trials and Criminal Trials. Detailed information including court names, locations, individuals, and trial numbers can be found using the PDF files attached to each subseries. A chart detailing the abbreviations used for each court can be found at the series level. This series is in good condition.
  - Civil Trials, 1982-1996; 1
    - December, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - January, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - February, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - March, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - April, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - May, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - June, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - July, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - August, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - September, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - October, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - November, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - December, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - January, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - February, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - March, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - April, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - May, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - June, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - July, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - August, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - September, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - November, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - December, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - January, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - February, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - March, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - April, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - May, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - June, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - July, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - August, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - September, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - October, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - December, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Untitled, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - January, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - February, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - March, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - April, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - May, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - June, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - July, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - August, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - September, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - October, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - December, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - January, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - February, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - March, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - April, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - May, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - June, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - July, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - August, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - September, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - October, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - November, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - December, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - January, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - February, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - March, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - April, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - June, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - July, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - August, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - October, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - November, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - December, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - January, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - February, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - March, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - May, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - June, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - August, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - September, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - October, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - November, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - December, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - January, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - February, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - March, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - April, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - May, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - June, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - July, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - August, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - September, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - October, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - November, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - January, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - February, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - March, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - April, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - May, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - June, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - July, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - August, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - October, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - November, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - December, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - January, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - February, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - March, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - April, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - May, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - June, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - July, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - August, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - September, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - October, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - November, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - December, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - January, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - February, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - March, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - April, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - May, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - June, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - July, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - August, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - September, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - October, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - November, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - December, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - January, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - February, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - March, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - April, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - May, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - June, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - July, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - August, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - September, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - October, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - November, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - December, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - January, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - February, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - March, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - April, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - May, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - June, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - July, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - August, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - September, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - October, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - November, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - December, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - January, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - February, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Criminal Trials, 1982-1996; 2
    - December, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - January, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - February, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - March, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - April, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - May, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - June, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - July, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - August, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - September, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - October, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - November, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - December, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - January, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - February, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - March, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - April, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - May, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - June, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - July, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - August, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - September, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - October, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - November, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - December, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Untitled, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - January, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - February, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - March, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - April, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - May, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - June, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - July, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - August, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - September, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - October, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - November, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - December, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - January, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - February, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - April, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - May, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - June, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - July, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - August, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - September, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - October, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - November, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - December, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - January, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - February, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - March, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - April, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - May, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - June, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - July, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - August, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - September, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - November, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - December, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - April, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - May, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - June, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - July, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - August, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - October, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - November, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - December, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - January, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - February, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - May, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - June, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - August, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - September, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - October, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - November, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - December, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - January, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - February, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - March, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - April, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - May, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - June, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - July, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - August, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - September, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - October, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - December, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - January, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - February, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - March, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - April, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - May, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - June, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - July, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - August, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - September, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - October, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - November, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - December, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - January, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - February, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - March, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - April, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - May, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - June, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - July, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - August, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - September, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - October, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - November, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - December, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - January, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - February, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - March, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - April, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - May, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - June, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - July, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - August, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - October, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - November, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - December, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - January, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - February, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - March, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - April, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - May, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - June, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - July, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - August, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - September, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - October, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - November, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - December, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - January, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - February, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - March, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - April, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - May, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - June, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - July, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - August, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - September, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - October, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - November, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - December, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - January, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - February, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 35)